<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swift on Learning w/ Swift</title>
    <link>//coryjpopp.com/tags/swift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swift on Learning w/ Swift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//coryjpopp.com/tags/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The differences between Float, Double, and CGFloat</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/the-differences-between-float-double-and-cgfloat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/the-differences-between-float-double-and-cgfloat/</guid>
      <description>Swift has three different data types to represent floating point numbers, which are numbers with a decimal points - each with their own characteristics and contexts in which they are used.
The choice between Float, Double, and CGFloat depends on your specific use case, but some of the main differences are:
Floats are more efficient on memory usage, yet are less precise. Doubles consume more memory than floats, but provide a wider range of representable values and greater accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singletons: what are they and when to use one</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/what-is-a-singleton-and-when-to-use-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/what-is-a-singleton-and-when-to-use-one/</guid>
      <description>Singletons restrict a class to a single instance, and provide a global point of access to that instance.
Singletons are:
Ideal for managing a limited or shared resource, such as a database connection, thread pool, or configuration settings. Ideal for global state use cases, such as settings, preferences, or user authentification purposes. Often, but not always lazily initialized, and don&amp;rsquo;t actually get created until they are requested. Can be used for a centrilized place for logging, tracing, or monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic setup of a UIViewController in UIKit</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/using-file-manager-to-find-assets-in-uikit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/using-file-manager-to-find-assets-in-uikit/</guid>
      <description>View Controllers in UIKit can best be described as containing one screen worth of information. Data, functions, UI - whatever the screen needs to be complete.
When we create a new view controller it contains the following minimal code to get the screen up and running, and allows us to easily customize our screen how we want it from there.
class ViewController: UIViewController { override func viewDidLoad() { super.viewDidLoad() // Do any additional setup after loading the view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Constraints to Generics in Swift</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/adding-constraints-to-generics-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/adding-constraints-to-generics-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Adding constraints to generics lets you narrow down what type of values you will be providing in your function while still maintaining the flexibility that generics allow.
In this example, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a constraint to Value that say whatever I pass in must conform to the Numeric protocol - meaning anything I pass to this function must be an array of integers, doubles, floats, or anything else that conforms to Numeric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular Progress Animation</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/circular-progress-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/circular-progress-animation/</guid>
      <description>This is undoubtably quite a lot of code that can be reduced, but I was happy with my first draft of this circular progress animation that I created in SwiftUI.
TimelineView() appears to be extremely efficient in creating animations that rely on a timer, without any of the inefficiencies of leaving a timer running constantly.
struct CircularProgress: View { var lineWidth: CGFloat = 40 @State var secondsCounter: Double = 0 @State var iconSizer: Bool = false var body: some View { TimelineView(.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Protocols in Swift</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/understanding-protocols-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/understanding-protocols-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Protocols in Swift allow us to create blueprints for how classes, structs and enums should work.
They allow us to define exactly what properties and functions data types that conform to our protocol must contain to be valid. Types that conform to protocols can contain more than what is required, but must at least contain the bare minimum as defined in the protocol.
They are useful for minimizing the amount of otherwise duplicate code within our data types, and guaranteeing that otherwise unrelated types play nicely together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing within Swift Playground</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/unit-testing-within-swift-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/unit-testing-within-swift-playground/</guid>
      <description>Creating unit tests in Swift Playground is an easy way to double-check that you&amp;rsquo;re getting the outcome you expect when developing new features.
In this example, I recreated the fizzbuzz challenge and ran it through multiple tests to ensure it was working as intended. The bottom line executes all of my tests within the FizzBuzzTests class.
import Foundation import XCTest class FizzBuzzTests: XCTestCase { let fizzArray = [3, 6, 9, 12, 18, 21, 24, 27] let buzzArray = [5, 10, 20, 25, 35, 40, 50, 55] let fizzbuzzArray = [15, 30, 45, 60, 75, 90, 105, 120] func testFizz() { for i in fizzArray { let result = fizzbuzz(number: i) XCTAssertEqual(result, &amp;#34;Fizz&amp;#34;) } } func testBuzz() { for i in buzzArray { let result = fizzbuzz(number: i) XCTAssertEqual(result, &amp;#34;Buzz&amp;#34;) } } func testFizzBuzz() { for i in fizzbuzzArray { let result = fizzbuzz(number: i) XCTAssertEqual(result, &amp;#34;FizzBuzz&amp;#34;) } } } func fizzbuzz(number: Int) -&amp;gt; String { switch (number % 3 == 0, number % 5 == 0) { case (true, false): return &amp;#34;Fizz&amp;#34; case (false, true): return &amp;#34;Buzz&amp;#34; case (true, true): return &amp;#34;FizzBuzz&amp;#34; case (false, false): return String(number) } } FizzBuzzTests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Updates Animation</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/live-updates-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/live-updates-animation/</guid>
      <description>I came across a simple yet beautiful animation in the New York Times app the other day denoting their live updates feed.
It has three dots, all with different shades of red, alternating to imply to the user that changes to the story are happening rapidly in real time.
I always love challenging myself to get better at animations within SwiftUI, so I set out to recreate this cool little design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swipe to delete from lists in SwiftUI</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/swipe-to-delete-from-lists-in-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/swipe-to-delete-from-lists-in-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>SwiftUI includes a native solution for a swipe to delete function from within lists, which works exactly as you would expect with just a few lines of additional code.
The code itself is simple, and involves us creating a ForEach of our array within our list, and adding a .onDelete modifier to trigger the removeItems function that we have created below our view body.
💡 It’s important to note that our .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Transparency to Sheets in SwiftUI</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/adding-transparency-to-sheets-in-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/adding-transparency-to-sheets-in-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>Native sheets in iOS are by default opaque, and require a bit of extra code to enable any form of transparency.
First we can create a new background view that conforms to UIViewRepresentable.
struct BackgroundClearView: UIViewRepresentable { func makeUIView(context: Context) -&amp;gt; UIView { let view = UIView() DispatchQueue.main.async { view.superview?.superview?.backgroundColor = .clear } return view } func updateUIView(_ uiView: UIView, context: Context) {} } And then we can use that transparent view as a background view within our sheet to enable transparency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Landed My First iOS Job</title>
      <link>//coryjpopp.com/posts/how-i-landed-my-first-ios-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//coryjpopp.com/posts/how-i-landed-my-first-ios-job/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago I started learning swift with absolutely zero prior programming experience, and recently landed my first job.
I wanted to give back to this community and share my experience — what worked for me, and what didn’t. Feel free to ask my anything or share your own insights.
Getting Started with iOS Paul Hudson has an excellent tutorial series called 100 Days of SwiftUI that starts at the absolute beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
